《嘻哈帝國》前情提要
Previously on Empire...
你覺得自己是被人推下樓的嗎
You think that someone pushed you?
SSK字幕組
我真的不知道
I really don't know.
SSK字幕組
弗雷達 你剛才唱的是弗蘭克·蓋澤斯嗎
Freda, did you say something about Frank Gathers?
是的 他是我的父親
Yeah, that's my father.
他在監獄中被謀殺了
He got murdered in prison.
里昂家族將在今年的美國之聲
The Lyon family will be performing
音樂獎現場表演
at this year's ASA awards.
賈馬爾
Jamal,
你知道D總監吧 美國之聲的
you know D-Major, musical director
-音樂總監 -當然
- for the ASAs. - Of course.
我只是想更專業一點 夥計
I try to keep things professional, man.
還因為你沒有出櫃
And because you're not out.
你知道我不想強迫你
You know I don't want to make you do anything
做任何你覺得不舒服的事情
you don't feel comfortable with.
提安娜在和你進行二重唱
Tiana's doing a duet with you on a song
而你說這首歌會衝上百萬銷量
you yourself told me would go platinum.
製作方想要她唱
The producers wanted her.
我打賭你肯定從沒提起過我
I bet you never even brought me up.
如果是我的話 我會嫉妒的
If it was me, I'd be jealous.
如果我姐姐擁有一切 而我一無所有
If my sister had everything and I had nothing.
你知道我很快就能結束九十天的戒毒
You know, I'm about to get my 90-day chip.
-卡蘿爾 -塔裏克
- Carol. - Tariq?
那麼 你為紐約警署工作
So, what, you working for the NYPD?
不 我很久以前就離開警署了
No, I quit the force a long time ago.
盧修斯 這位女士是誰
Lucious, who is this lady?
她是莉亞·沃克 盧修斯的母親
This is Leah Walker, Lucious' mother.
她只是個瘦小的老太太
She's just a little, old lady,
沒有什麼好害怕的
and there is nothing to fear.
我遺憾我之前竟然如此軟弱
I'm sorry I was too weak
不能在有機會的時候殺了你
to kill you when I had the chance.
注意 明天就是美國之聲的表演 這首歌
Now, tomorrow's the ASAs, and this song
必須成為全場的矚目所在
has to be the highlight of the show.
我想要全世界都為此興奮 好嗎
I want the entire world talking about it, okay?
開始
Bring us in.
停 停 停 停
Stop, stop, stop, stop,
你開始的時候太躊躇了
you're too tentative on the entrance.
知道了嗎 開始
You know what? Start again.
停 記住
Stop. Remember
這是一首搖籃曲 聽著 我們要在這裏
it's a lullaby. Look, we're gonna be here
練習一整夜 直到你們找到感覺
all night until you get this right.
好的 再來一次
Okay, start one more time.
二 三 四
Two, three, four.
不 不
No, no.
絃樂這樣進來
I want the strings to come in just like that.
我們再來一次
Let's try that again.
這個和弦 呃
That chord, uh...
不 不要疲憊
No, tired is not an option.
打起精神來
Get it together.
再來一次
Bring me back in one more time.
先等一下 加上 加上
Stop for a second. Just give me... g-give me
鼓聲 還有貝斯
drums and give me bass.
這個節奏
That pace...
正是我們需要的
that's where we need to be at.
停 我們接近了
Stop. We're getting there.
我們接近了
We're getting there.
再來
Bring me back in.
一定要乾脆
Make sure it's strong.
絕不能犯錯
There's no room for error.
對了
Yeah.
這才是美國之聲的水準
This is the ASAs.
我很喜歡 繼續
I like that, keep going.
盡情地
Take us there.
很好
Yeah.
貝斯 很好 繼續
Bass, yeah, keep going.
我非常享受
I'm liking this a lot.
很好
Yeah.
-稍等我一下 -好的
- Give me a couple minutes here. - Yes.
你們的演奏真是太棒了
You guys sound amazing.
樂隊真厲害啊 盧修斯
Band sounds great, Lucious.
謝謝 琦琦
Thanks, Cook.
他們進入狀態了 有什麼事嗎
They're getting there. What's up?
你媽媽還好嗎
How's your mama?
她還瘋著
She's still crazy.
她還在你家裏 不是嗎
She's still at your house, right?
是
Yeah.
-嗯 -怎麼了
- Mm-hmm. - What's up?
嗯 盧修斯 聽著 我需要你休息一下
Um, Lucious, look, I need you to get some rest.
你已經忙一整晚了
You've been at this all night.
讓樂隊休息一下
Give the band a break.
我死了 才會休息
I'll rest when I'm dead,
明天就是美國之聲的表演了
but right now we got the ASAs tomorrow,
他們的演奏必須無懈可擊
and they got to be airtight.
你知道你這麼做不是為了美國之聲
You know that this ain't about the ASAs.
是為了避開你的母親
This is about you avoiding your mother.
你為什麼讓那個女人
Why you letting that woman
這麼對你
do this to you?
聽著 你別管 琦琦
Look, stay in your lane, Cookie.
嗨 盧修斯 過來
Hey, Lucious, come here.
盧修斯
Lucious...
你把自己投入工作裏
you're working yourself
這樣就能避開她
so hard so you can avoid.
你必須解決問題
You have to deal with this.
聽著 你昨晚沒回家
Look, you didn't go home last night.
前天晚上一直待在辦公室
The other night you stayed in your office.
我告訴過你 那個女人很危險
I told you, the woman's dangerous,
我不相信她
and I don't trust her.
可以了嗎
All right?
我能回去工作了嗎 行嗎
Can I get back to work, please?
好的 盧修斯
All right, Lucious.
好的 重新開始 親愛的
All right, count us back in, sweetheart.
離第54屆美國
We are one day away
之聲大獎還有一天的時間
from the 54th Annual American Sound Awards.
所有人都在問
The big question everybody is asking:
哪一個里昂將會
which Lyon will come...
明晚福克斯電視台 第54屆
Tomorrow night on Fox, the 54th...
明天雨將停 所以
The rain is supposed to clear up for tomorrow, so it should be...
沃克女士
Ms. Walker.
吐司 火腿 炒雞蛋 都是您喜歡的
Toast, ham, scrambled eggs, everything you like.
不 還有調料
No. Seasoning.
什麼
Pardon me?
你沒有給吃的加調料
You don't season your food.
我不吃
I'm not eating it.
給我咖啡就好
Just give me coffee.
走上紅毯
...covering the red carpet.
此前預測
Forecast earlier...
我十分榮幸能夠被提名
It's an honor to be nominated...
我是說 榮幸之至
I mean, a big honor...
我真的非常興
and I'm really exci...
我以為我已經把你炒了
I thought I fired you.
哼
Hmm.
凱蒂·佩裏 泰勒·斯威夫特
Katy Perry, Taylor Swift.
啊 好吧 我等不及要看泰勒·斯威夫特
Ah, well, I can't wait to see what Taylor Swift...
他的提名熱曲
In the video for his nominated
"Boom Boom Boom Boom"的MV中
hit song, "Boom Boom Boom Boom,"
盧修斯·里昂分享了
Lucious Lyon shares
一個令人心碎的故事
a heartbreaking story about his
他患有躁鬱癥的母親自殺了
bipolar mother who took her own life.
經歷著痛苦與貧窮
It's a rare look inside
這是一個人的個人經歷中
one man's very personal journey
極為不同尋常的一面
through pain and poverty.
盧修斯·里昂今年的經歷
Lucious Lyon's own journey this year
可謂引人注目
has been remarkable, having served
他在監獄裏待了三個月
three months in prison for what many
而很多人認為該刑事起訴基於種族偏見
consider a racially motivated prosecution,
他失去過
and then losing
又奪回了
and regaining control
對帝國公司的控制
of his Empire Entertainment,
只要出現
only to emerge with...
砰
Boom.
他職業生涯中最振奮忍心的時刻之一
...one of the biggest hits of his career.
♪ Bang, bang, bang, bang
♪ Boom, boom, boom, boom ♪
砰
Boom.
- Boom.
♪ Bang, bang, bang, bang
他一直是個騙子
He's always been a liar.
一個厚顏無恥的騙子
A bald-faced liar.
♪ Bang, bang, bang, bang. ♪
嘻哈帝國
第二季  第十七集
-謝謝你 威廉 -好的
- Thank you, William. - Okay.
字幕由SSK字幕組傾情譯制
僅供學習，勿用於商，轉載請註明出處，版權歸片方所有
嗨 琦琦 看 朗達剛剛讓我試了這條裙子
Hey, Cook, look, Rhonda just fit me in this dress.
實在太棒了 是不是
It's banging, right?
我穿這個去美國之聲
So what do you think
翻譯  扣子
你覺得怎樣
about me wearing it to the ASAs?
謝謝  當然 不過不要跟我一起
Thanks. Sure, but not if you're going with me.
你需要跟朗達說一說
You need to tell Rhonda to get you something
翻譯  愚人捕漁
讓她幫你找一件稍微得體一點的
a little more appropriate.
你看起來像個廉價的
You look like a cheap
妓女
prostitute.
翻譯  葉子
那你覺得盧修斯會找誰當女伴
So what skank you think Lucious is taking?
姑娘 我不知道 我也不關心
Girl, I don't know, and I don't care.
翻譯  You
我只關心 他們父子都能出現在舞台上
All I care about is getting those boys up on that stage,
因為星期天一到 所有的頭條
because come Sunday, all the headlines
翻譯  方塊
都會稱我們"第一嘻哈家族"
are gonna be calling us "The First Family of Hip Hop,"
校對  扣子
這才是我關心的
and that is all I care about.
校對 小P
姑娘 猜猜我在大瓊斯街餐廳
Girl, guess who I ran into at the restaurant
遇見了誰
on Great Jones Street.
塔裏克·卡曾斯 記得他嗎
Tariq Cousins, remember him?
身材火辣的塔裏克
Fine-ass Tariq?
-怪人塔裏克 -正是
- Tariq the Freak? - Yeah.
時軸 喵喵
-那個警察 -不 不
- The cop? - No, no...
他不在費城警察局干了
he's not working for the Philly PD anymore.
他現在住在紐約
He lives here in New York.
姑娘
Girl...
他剛邀請我去拉維媞卡斯共進晚餐
he just invited me to dinner at Laviticus.
噢 你知道 我要問問朗達
Ooh, you know, I'm gonna ask Rhonda
能不能借一下這條裙子
if I could borrow this dress
壓制  呵呵姐
萬一把塔裏克給驚艷到了呢
just in case Tariq wants to freak!
是的 塔裏克
Yes, Tariq!
總監 小P
♪ Said I got to do, got to do my own thing
♪ I do my own thing
♪ Do my own thing
♪ I got to do my own thing
♪ Do my own thing ♪
♪ Yo
♪ Whoop
♪ Can't nobody tell me
♪ What to do, tell me what to do
♪ Can't nobody, ugh
♪ Uh, everything I do
♪ Is me, what you mean?
♪ We gon' keep it 100
♪ A bean
♪ No stranger to struggling
♪ Making something out of nothing
- ♪ Yeah
- ♪ Uh, yeah, for nothin'
- ♪ It's somethin', I do it
- ♪ Oh, yeah
♪ I want it, I get it
♪ So I'm gettin' to it
♪ Do my own thing
♪ Came this far, it's all me
♪ Doin' what I do
- ♪ I got to do my own thing
- ♪ Yeah
- ♪ My way, my way
- ♪ I got to do it my way
♪ Doin' my own thing
♪ Trippin' on
♪ Nobody
♪ Makin' my moves
♪ I got to do my own thing
♪ My way, my way, my way
♪ Yeah, I got to do it my way.
行嗎
So?
我是說 很顯然 我們還沒完成
I mean, obviously, we ain't done yet,
不過你覺得呢
but what do you think?
我 呃
I, uh...
說實在的
on the real...
這種感覺很新
...that's that brand-new right there.
你很有天分
You got something.
是嗎
Yeah?
是的
You do.
是的 很讓人激動
Yeah, it's fire.
喲 說真的 他聽歌可是比我媽
Yo, seriously, though, he's a tougher critic
-還挑剔的 -我知道 哇
- than my mom. - I know, wow.
謝謝
Thank you.
噢 不 不 不 不
Oh, no, no, no, no,
是你們兩個做到的
the two of y'all did that.
真的 你有魔法
For real, you got magic.
-謝謝 -噢
- Thank you. - Oh!
我們不能失去它
We can't lose it!
-那是魔法 -這就是關鍵 對嗎
- That's magic. - That's what's up, right?
對 聽著 我要回店裏
Right, look, I'm-a get back to the shop, cut some heads.
-好 -D總監 夥計
- Yeah. - D-Major, man,
我很感激 很榮幸
I appreciate it; it's a pleasure.
好的
All right.
過後我們再聯繫
I'll catch y'all later.
-好的 弗雷達 -好的
- All right, Freda. - All right.
賈 是時候讓你媽媽放手了
J... it's time to let your mom go.
你不是認真的吧
You ain't serious?
我認真的
I'm dead-ass.
別這樣 德裏克
Hell no, Derek.
那可是我母親
That's my mother,
還有 我喜歡跟她一起工作
and-and besides, I love working with her.
她製作了整個黑與白專輯
She's producing the whole damn Black and White album.
賈馬爾
Jamal...
比起你的爸爸媽媽能為你做的
you're so much bigger than whatever
現在你完全可以超越了
your moms and pops could do for your sound right now.
更何況他們對你還產生了扭曲作用
Plus they keep you twisted up.
現在你不能在音樂上
It's time for you to be more
只當媽媽的乖兒子了
than a musical mama's boy.
你應該提升自己的水平
You should level up.
讓我來製作你的下一張專輯
Let me produce your next album.
你想製作我的下一張專輯
You want to produce my next album?
是的
Yeah.
除非我對你來說不夠大牌
Unless I ain't big enough for you.
偽裝後的聚會
Party with disguises.
四個字
Ten letters.
可不是嘛
You tell me.
假面舞會
Masked ball.
你還好嗎 奶奶
So, you good, Grandma?
吃得還好嗎
Are you eating right?
有在吃藥了嗎
You taking your medication?
藥太多 我吃得都快噎住了
So many pills, make me choke.
為什麼都不能弄成一片呢
Why can't they put it all in one?
不過你感覺好多了 對嗎
But you feel better, right?
有人帶你出去散散步嗎
Do the staff take you out to get some fresh air?
家裏傭人什麼的人太多了
So many maids and people working in this house,
感覺跟《飄》裏一樣
it feels like Gone with the Wind.
不過大家都很尊重你 是嗎
But everybody treats you respectfully, right?
我不喜歡被排除在外
I don't like being left out.
排除在外 怎麼會
Left out, how?
電視上都在說
They talk about it on the TV,
我知道德懷特會登台
and I know Dwight's gonna be in it.
您在說美國之聲嗎
You talking about the ASAs?
他們說我的整個家族都會登台表演
They said my whole family's performing,
但是沒人邀請我
but nobody invited me.
你知道嗎
Do you know
我從來沒見過他在舞台上表演
I've never even seen him on a stage?
盧修斯·里昂
Lucious Lyon.
聽著 我 我很想帶你去美國之聲 奶奶
Look, I'd-I'd love to take you to the ASAs, Grandma.
我得去問問帝國的人事部門
I'd need to talk to Empire's PR department
看看能不能多要一張票
to see if we can even get an extra ticket.
讓德懷特去問
Tell Dwight to talk to them.
他能幫我弄到票
He can get me a ticket.
你需要一條新裙子
You'd need a new dress...
我必須
and I would have to
問問爸爸 這事情有點棘手
run it by Pop. It could be a tricky situation.
因為他希望我死了
Because he wishes I was dead.
奶奶 他不會希望你
Grandma, he doesn't wish that you were...
他在自己的MV裏就是
That's what he told everybody
這麼跟所有人說的
in that movie he made.
只是影片嘛
That was just a movie.
好嗎 只是個MV 虛構的
Okay, it was a story, make-believe.
現在 問題是
Now, the problem...
我不會跟任何人說他撒謊
I won't tell anybody he lied,
如果你是害怕這一點
if that's what you're scared of.
我只是想看看我的孫子們
I just want to see my grandbabies up there
登台表演 僅此而已
on that stage, that's all.
如果被人發現的話
It would destroy his credibility
他的信譽就算完了 奶奶
if anybody found out, Grandma.
對帝國也不好 而且
It'd be bad for Empire, and it would be
真的 真的對爸爸影響不好
really, really bad for Pop.
親愛的 到時候會有許多美麗的姑娘
Honey, there's gonna be so many pretty girls there,
沒有人會注意旁邊的
nobody's even gonna look sideways
一個小老太太
at a little old lady.
嗨 朗達
Hey, Rhonda.
-嗨 -哦 嗨
- Hey. - Oh, hey.
對不起 你有空嗎
Sorry, do you have a minute?
嗯 我現在要去試衣間 有一堆要
Well, I'm on my way to a fitting for a bunch
上美國之聲的歌手在等著我 嗯
of artists for the ASAs, uh, well...
-我一會去找你們 先去吧 -好的
- I'll meet you guys there, just go ahead without me. - Sure.
嗨 抱歉
Hey, sorry.
抱歉 我幾乎沒有時間
Sorry, I barely have a minute.
-什麼事 -唔
- What's up? - Um...
你前天沒去練瑜伽 呃
You weren't at yoga the other day and, uh,
我本以為我能見到你的 我有給你發短信
I thought I'd see you there, and I've been texting you,
你沒有回 不像你的作風 所以
and it's just not like you to not respond, so...
我給這些歌手配衣服
I've just been crazed
我都忙瘋了 就是這樣
dressing all these artists, that's all.
哦 好吧
Oh, okay.
哦
Oh.
哦 老天 原來是因為我肚子開始凸起來了
Oh, my God, I'm starting to show,
很抱歉讓你難過 朗達
and it's painful for you, I'm sorry, Rhonda.
-不 -我真笨
- No. - I'm so stupid.
-不 不 安妮卡 -我本該考慮到的
- No, no, Anika. - I should be more sensitive.
我沒事 真的
I'm fine, honestly.
真為你高興
I'm happy for you.
不過我要問你一個問題
But I was gonna ask you a question, actually.
你記不記得
Do you remember when you came over
你來我育兒室的那天
that day to see the nursery and...
你穿的那雙可愛的鞋子
you were wearing those really cute shoes?
鞋底是紅色的
They had red soles.
是魯布托 對吧
They were Louboutins, right?
哦 天哪 我都不記得
Oh, God, I don't remember
我穿了什麼
what I was wearing.
為什麼
Why?
只是我感覺
Just because I feel like
它們很適合全天穿
they're good day-to-night shoes,
所以我想你那天晚上會不會穿
so I was wondering if you were wearing them that night.
穿了嗎
Were you?
我們那晚見面了嗎
Did we see each other that night?
我不知道
I don't know.
有嗎
Did we?
好的 那
Okay, so...
想像一個冬日僊境
think a winter wonderland.
有雪
Snow...
冰柱 銀色的蛋糕
icicles, an all silver cake.
那會很閃亮的
That's gonna be shiny.
所有雜誌社已經爭著
All the mags are already scrambling
搶奪新郎新娘的第一組照片了
to get the first pictures of the bride and groom.
我不知道我是不是希望狗仔隊出現在婚禮上
Look, I don't even know if I want paparazzi at our wedding.
但是如果我們給《美國週刊》獨家報道
But if we give Us Weekly an exclusive,
他們或許會在網站上
maybe they'll highlight
重點介紹我的音樂
some of my music on their site.
只是一家雜誌 我覺得不會讓婚禮跌份的
It's just one magazine. I don't think that'll cheapen it.
- ♪ Do it .
- ♪ Tell mama you know I...
聽著 勞拉 寶貝 別自責
Look, Laura, bae, I don't want you to blame yourself.
是我不好
It's my fault.
- ♪ Say it
- ♪ You gon' have to do less when you...
但是你的事業還不會像我們期望的那樣上升
But your career ain't gonna take off the way we wanted it to.
- ♪ Show it
- ♪ See, you gon' need to do more than just
- ♪ Prove it
你不再相信我了
You don't believe in me anymore.
♪ You know
♪ Say it, baby
♪ Do it, baby...
聽著 我們倆都很努力
Look, we worked hard, the both of us.
你也唱了幾首好歌
You did a couple dope songs.
還在提安娜的巡迴演出上做開場表演
You opened up for Tiana on tour...
只是還沒有火起來
but it just hasn't popped yet.
♪ Baby...
但是你看
But look...
我們還是可以給《美國週刊》獨家報道
we can still give Us Weekly that exclusive.
別說了
Stop.
♪ See your body move in different ways...
我的夢想就是嫁給你
My dream is marrying you.
那對我來說已經夠了
That's enough for me right now.
♪ You make me come through
♪ I get so close to you.
卡蘿爾說的事是真的
Carol's story panned out.
塔裏克2010年就從警察局離職了
Tariq quit the force in 2010.
為什麼
Why?
不知道 文件封起來了
Don't know, files are sealed.
可能是警務政策什麼的
Some kind of police policy.
瑟斯看不了
Even Thirst couldn't open it up,
也就是說
which means...
現在他是聯邦探員
Which means he's a Fed now.
-就是這個意思 -嗯 但是
- That's what it means. - Yeah, but
問題是 現在 為什麼聯邦探員
this is the problem, now, I mean, why would
還想糾纏我
the Feds want to rumble with me again,
尤其是羅克珊·福特都碰壁了
especially after that little fiasco with Roxanne Ford?
那個人 塔裏克 我是說
Now your boy, Tariq, I mean,
我沒有跟他相處過
I ain't never hung with him,
不過就算是我們窮困潦倒的時候
but he was always respectful
他也是客客氣氣的
back when we was grinding,
不過他和你妹妹
but him and your sister, that's...
說真的 他怎麼會想和卡蘿爾混在一起
Exactly, why would he want to get mixed up with Carol?
大家都知道卡蘿爾是癮君子
Everybody know Carol's a crackhead...
還有三個私生子
and she got three illegitimate kids.
這根本說不通啊
That don't make sense.
他們又不聰明
They not slick.
瑟斯對塔裏克的調查可能
Thirsty might be done
就此收手 但我才不會收手
investigating Tariq, but I'm not.
說到那個癮君子
Speaking about crackheads,
你為什麼要帶她去美國之聲
why are you taking her to the ASAs?
呃 我還以為等我有伴的
Yeah, well, I heard you was gonna ask me
你才會問我呢
until you found out I had a date.
不 好吧 我要帶個超模去
No, that's all right, I'm-a take a supermodel.
噢 盧修斯 沒人喜歡你的肥屁股
Oh, Lucious, don't nobody want your fat ass.
恩 我是該胖的地方胖
Yeah, I'm only fat where it counts.
嘴上威風
In the mouth.
♪ Come and get it, come and get it
♪ You know we got it over here, be clear
♪ Baby, I know that you're wit' it
♪ Come and get it, uh
♪ Ten bottles at the table
♪ You know we got it over here, be clear, baby...
-哎呦喂 不得了了 -琦琦
- Well, well, well. - Cookie.
這不是塔裏克·卡曾斯嗎
If it isn't Tariq Cousins.
你還好嗎 沒嚇到你吧
You okay? Did I scare you?
沒有 很高興見到你
No, no, good to see you.
可別撒謊啊
Eh, don't lie.
你看起來像見鬼一樣
Look like you seen a ghost.
我可沒我妹妹那麼好騙
I'm not as gullible as my sister.
恩恩
Uh-huh.
哦 對了 另外 她不知道我來了
Ooh, uh, FYI, she doesn't know I'm here.
-嗯哼 -卡蘿爾總是遲到
- Uh-huh. - Carol, she always late.
是啊
Yeah.
我記得你經常幫她解決麻煩
I remember you bailing her out of a bunch of jams.
恩 一家人嘛 應該的
Yeah, family, that's what you do.
當然 你也撬了她很多男朋友
Of course, you stole a bunch of her boyfriends, too,
你和盧修斯搞上之前
and didn't she even hook up
她不是正在跟盧修斯約會嗎
with, uh, Lucious before y'all hooked up?
聽著 可不是你想的那樣
See, that's not quite how that happened,
怪人塔裏克
Tariq the Freak.
怪人
The Freak.
聽著 我知道你是聯邦探員
Look, I know you a Fed,
你最好別想著
so you better not be planning
從我妹妹下手
on putting the squeeze on my sister
從我或者我家這裏挖出什麼
to try to come for me or my family.
你有不可告人的秘密嗎
You got something to hide?
只是單純的約會
It's an innocent date.
我對她有感覺 想跟她在一起 明白嗎
I ran into her and wanted to hang, you know.
-嗯 -紐約
- Hmm. - New York
比皮條客的心都冷酷
is colder than a pimp's heart
一年就65000美元
on $65K a year.
-嗯 -我都懷念費城了
- Mm. - I miss Philly.
沒錯 我們總說你是個好人
Yeah, we always said you was one of the good ones.
恩
Yeah,
你從沒忘江湖規則
you never forgot the "G" Code.
沒錯 從沒忘過
Nah, never that.
琦琦 我是在街頭長大的
I grew up on those streets, Cookie.
江湖規則
That code means more
比我戴過的任何徽章
to me than any badge I wear,
我宣讀過的任何誓言都重要
any oath of office I take...
正因為這樣 我很驚訝
which is why I'm surprised you still
你還跟盧修斯在一起 因為他
rocking with Lucious when he's the one who
違背了規則
violated it.
盧修斯嗎
Lucious?
是啊
Yeah.
他殺了你表親 邦基
Yeah, he killed your cousin, Bunkie.
希望你
You enjoy
在我和盧修斯
your dinner
的俱樂部裏 晚餐愉快
at my and Lucious' club.
對了 小心點
Oh, and watch out.
我妹妹有皰疹
My sister has herpes.
希望這話不會太遲
Hope it's not too late.
美國之聲倒計時開始了
The countdown to the ASAs is on.
你最愛的明星會穿什麼
What will your favorite star be wearing?
誰會成為最佳著裝
Who will be best dressed,
最差著裝 還有最重要的是
worst, and most importantly,
他們將攜誰出席
who will they be posing with?
敬請期待
Stay tuned.
今晚這裏肯定會熱鬧得不行
Tonight's gonna be a madhouse.
那麼 你來負責賈馬爾
Okay, so you handle Jamal 'cause he's got to get
因為他會最受媒體關注
the most press out of this, uh...
史蒂夫 能迴避一下嗎
Steve, can y'all excuse me for a second?
昨晚和塔裏克玩得開心嗎
So, did you have fun with Tariq last night?
事實上 是很開心
As a matter of fact, I did,
他跟我說 你和他打招呼了
and he told me you came to say hey.
琦琦 你就不能不插手嗎
Why don't you just back off, Cookie?
塔裏克喜歡的人是我 不是你
Tariq's interested in me, not you.
你跟他說了什麼
What did you tell him?
你說呢 我有那麼蠢嗎
What do you think, I'm stupid?
他沒在調查任何人
He's not investigating anybody.
是嗎 沒有嗎
Oh, he's not?
-沒有 -好的
- No. - Okay.
不 我們就是聊天
No, we just talked.
一直在聊天
All we did was talk.
好吧 你們聊了什麼
Oh, well, what did y'all talk about?
他跟我說拉希姆一條腿
He told me that Raheem had to get his leg
膝蓋一下都截掉了
cut off from the knee down.
拉希姆 真的嗎
Raheem, really?
真的嗎
Really?
他在利用你呢 你個蠢貨
He is working you, stupid.
不 他沒有
No, he is not!
你知道嗎 好男人喜歡我
You know, it is possible
是有可能的 琦琦
for a good man to like me, Cookie,
而這一次 你不准撬牆腳
and this time, you're not gonna steal him
也別想在我心裏敗壞他的形象
or try to poison him in my head.
過來
Come here.
過來 來這邊跟我說話
Come here. Come over here and talk to me.
坐下 你離我那麼遠
Sit down, you're all the way over there.
你太緊張了
You're all tense.
你昨晚和塔裏克喝酒了 不是嗎
You had a drink last night with Tariq, didn't you?
天 我跟你說過 如果你再上癮
Man, I told you, if you fall off again,
你就得給我滾蛋 我不是開玩笑的
that your ass was out, and I meant that!
你總是撬走我的男朋友 你知道吧
You know you always stealing my boyfriends, right?
你奪走了肖恩
You stole Sean,
然後是卡爾 是 還有盧修斯
then Kyle, yeah... Lucious.
對
Right...
對 因為
right, 'cause...
如果我沒有出現
if I'd never showed up,
盧修斯可能會跟你終老
Lucious would have ended up with you.
是 他先遇到的我
Yeah, well, he met me first,
然後你才半路殺出來
then here you come.
琦琦來了
Here come Cookie.
每次你舊癮復發
Every time you fall off the wagon,
我就受指責
I get the blame.
我已經受夠了 卡蘿爾
I'm sick of it, Carol.
你真的相信
You really believe
你該過上我現在的生活嗎
that you deserve my life.
你這腦殘真的相信
Your sick ass really believe that.
-坎迪斯說得沒錯 -坎迪斯
- Candace was right about you. - Candace.
是的 她對你的評價
Yeah, she was so right
完全正確
about you.
你根本對我
You don't give a damn
毫不關心
about me.
你只關心怎樣
All you care about is making
讓自己感覺更好
yourself feel better.
這就是為什麼你把我留在身邊
That's why you keep me around.
你自己一無所有
You ain't got nothing of your own,
只依賴盧修斯給你什麼
just what Lucious is letting you have.
你是這麼覺得的
That's how you feel?
是 事實如此
Yeah, that's how it is.
好吧
Okay...
好吧 滾吧 卡蘿爾
well, then bounce, Carol.
趕緊滾
Bounce your ass
滾出我的公司
out of my company.
你就是那麼想的
That's how you feel?
我不關心你
I don't care about you?!
那把你那些破爛搬出我的公寓
Then get your raggedy stuff out of my apartment!
既然我不關心你 那你就那麼做吧
That's what you can do since I don't care about you,
還有 別妄想美國之聲了
and you know what, forget about the ASAs!
因為我不會帶一個管不住自己的癮君子
'Cause I'm not taking no washed up crackhead
去美國之聲
to no ASAs!
因為你不讓我尷尬才怪
'Cause you ain't gonna embarrass me.
出去
Get out!
我不關心你
I don't care about you.
我叫你滾
I said get out!
出去
Get out!
說我不關心你
I don't care about you.
♪ Gonna tell a story of
SSK字幕組
♪ A fella who fell in love
♪ I said that I had before
♪ But now I'm even mesure, phonetically in my
♪ Heart
♪ I thought that I would get the less
♪ But now I see I get the best
♪ No more time wasted, not trying to make a statement
♪ The words are coming out my head
♪ At night
♪ In the moonlight
♪ I see your smiling eyes...
嗨 哥們 我很喜歡
Hey, man, I love that.
你知道我最喜歡的是什麼嗎
You know what I really love about it?
是你的聲音 哥們
It's your voice, man.
♪ You are my butterfly
它能引起共鳴
It resonates.
♪ You knew I'd be your man
我覺得拍子還是太慢了
I still say the tempo is too slow.
你得幫我改一下
You need to work on that.
好 我能辦到
Yeah, I could do that.
♪ You needed me
嗨 賈馬爾
Hey, Jamal.
♪ And now just like...
-答應我 -嗯
- Promise me something. - Mm-hmm.
如果你晚上看到
When you see me tonight,
我和夏奈爾一起走紅毯
on the carpet with Chanel,
別往心裏去
don't let that mean anything to you.
♪ I wanna say
♪ I know I...
你知道有多少
You know how many rappers
說唱歌手和製作人
and producers are gonna be
會帶著超模走紅毯充當掩護嗎
on the carpet with supermodels as their beard?
不是 那很奇怪
No, it's wack.
聽著 哥們 放鬆
Listen, man, relax.
只是一個晚上
It's just one night.
你 放開我 你個傢伙
Yo, get off me, man!
老兄 別再那樣靠近我 老兄
Bro, don't you ever come at me like that again, bro.
-什麼 -你聽到我的話了
- What? - You heard me, what?
我發誓 如果你再像剛那樣碰我
I swear, if you ever touch me like that ag...
喲 盧修斯 這是你兒子
Yo, Lucious, this your son?
喲 你需要跟他談談
Yo, you need to talk to him.
因為真是讓人不爽
'Cause this ain't cool.
D總監是個深櫃吧
I see D-Major's still on the DL.
肯定招惹過你了
Must've got to you.
你知道
You knew?
真正的狗還不知道哪個是滿嘴謊話的婊子嗎
A real dog can always tell a fake bitch.
老爸 別說這些傻話了
Dad, can you stop with all the stupid riddles.
你是怎麼知道的
How did you know?
我在這個圈子混了這麼久 你以為
I've been in this business so long, you think I don't
我真的一點都不瞭解這個圈裏的人嗎
know a little bit about everybody in this industry?
D總監是個有才的音樂製作人
And even though D-Major's a talented producer,
但他的私生活可不是什麼秘密
his secret life is not so secretive.
所有人都知道
And everybody knows how he likes to turn
他喜歡勾搭有錢的小伙子
rich boys into his little bitch.
你怎麼知道不是我主動勾搭的
How do you know I ain't turning him into my little bitch?
是他先撩我的 不是我先撩他的
He came on to me. I didn't come on to him.
還用說嗎
Exactly.
我敢說 他一定是上面那個
I bet you he's on top.
-你真噁心 老爸 -不
- You're disgusting, Dad. - No.
讓人噁心的是 你在我錄音棚裏幹的事
What's disgusting is what you're doing in my studio.
誰都有可能進來 撞見你們的好事
Anybody could've walked in here and saw you,
我教過你該怎麼做吧
and I taught you better than that.
兔子還不吃窩邊草呢
You don't crap where you eat.
是啊 你說得沒錯 你看上去很高興嘛
Yeah, Dad, you're right. You're enjoying this.
高興什麼
Enjoying what?
你以為我高興
You think I enjoy watching
看著自己的兒子變成
my son become some closet
某個不敢出櫃的混蛋的小受嗎
phony's little bitch?
聽著 兒子 我試過去理解你的生活方式
Look, man, I've tried to be sensitive to your way of life.
什麼叫 理解我的生活方式
There it is. S-Sensitive to-to my way of life.
我試著瞭解你的想法
I've listened to you.
容忍一些事
I've tried to tolerate something
容忍我天生無法忍受的事
that is intolerable to my nature.
我努力去理解你
I tried to understand
尊重你的選擇
and be respectful of your choices,
但你卻不尊重我
but you don't respect me.
你直接把反常的生活方式
You just keep throwing this unnatural way
赤裸裸地甩在我面前
of life into my face.
我試著以男人的身份和你談這個問題
I've tried to talk to you as a man,
但你卻跟個小娘們兒似的
but all you do is turn into some little girl,
還因為我20年前做過的事
mad about something I did to you
-生我的氣 -20年前
- 20 years ago. - 20 years ago.
你還因為你媽在40年前把你扔進水裏
You're crying like a little bitch about your mother
哭得跟個娘們兒一樣呢
throwing you in some water 40 years ago,
你有什麼好說
so what does that say about you?
你甚至都不敢擦掉眼淚 直視那個女人的眼睛
Can't even look the woman in the eyes without crying.
至少我沒有哭
I'm not crying.
你還好意思一直教訓我
Always telling me,
"賈馬爾 別娘們兮兮的
"Jamal, don't be a little sissy bitch.
多花點心思到音樂上吧」
Put it into music."
我倒想跟你說 盧修斯 別跟個女人一樣 多花點心思到
Well, Lucious, don't be a sissy bitch. Put it into mu...
我對你除了失望
You ain't nothing to me
還是失望
but a disappointment.
等你死於艾滋的那天
And the day you die from AIDS...
我會舉杯慶祝
...I'm gonna celebrate.
你以為盧修斯不可能再刷新他的下限
Right when you think that Lucious can't stoop any lower,
-那你就錯了 他每次都會 -好吧 他幹嘛了
- he does, every single time. - Okay, what did he do?
當時我和D總監在錄音棚
So I'm in the studio with D-Major,
因為他想為我和弗雷達製作音樂
'cause he wants to produce me and Freda.
-然後盧修斯 -什麼 你剛說什麼
- And then Lucious... - Wh-Wh-What did you just say?
媽 我已經拒絕他了 好嗎
Mom, I told him no, okay?
但現在我必須和更多的音樂製作人合作
But at this point, I should work with more producers.
好吧 你又重新和弗雷達合作了
Okay, so you're back working with Freda?
這又怎麼了 這根本不是重點好嗎
Why is that important? That's not even the issue.
-賈馬爾 跟我來 -盧修斯進了錄音棚
- Jamal, come on. - Lucious comes into the studio...
不 不 不 不 你不該和弗雷達合作 賈馬爾
No, no, no, no, you need to let Freda go, Jamal.
-不 媽媽 不 -你必須遠離她
- No, Ma. Mom, no. - You got to let her go.
這和弗雷達沒有關繫好嗎 我說的是盧修斯
This is not about Freda. This is about Lucious.
我說的是我自己的事
This is about me.
我們也說過的 你不能像過去那樣了
And the things that we said that you can't come back from.
嗨 嗨 嗨
Hey, hey, hey.
你還記得那個
You remember that prosecutor
一心想搞垮你爸的檢察官嗎
who was so hell-bent on trying to bring your father down?
記得 呃 叫蒂茨·麥基
Yeah, um, Tits McGee.
對 就是那個賤人
Yeah, that bitch.
聯邦的人現在還在調查我們呢
Well, the Feds are still coming for us.
知道嗎
Okay?
所以我們必須要低調 懂了嗎
So we need to lay low, all right?
我們所有人都必須小心
Be easy. Be careful. All of us.
我們必須保持低調 所有人嗎
We need to lay low? All of us?
才不是 他們只在調查盧修斯
Nah, they're coming for Lucious.
那跟我又有什麼關係呢
And tell me why I should care about that.
他跟我的音樂又有什麼關係呢
I got to worry about what's wrong with him and my music.
我為什麼要為了他放棄我的音樂
What would be my incentive to let go of my music for him?
你不是想知道我為什麼可以提前釋放嗎
You ever wonder how I got out early on good behavior?
講真 我想過 你可能是告發了什麼人吧 但我
Honestly, I-I assumed you informed on somebody, but I...
他的名字
His name...
你看見是誰開的槍嗎
Did you see who shot him?
你能告訴我們開槍人的名字嗎
Can you name that shooter?
弗蘭克·蓋澤斯
Frank Gathers.
媽 你居然出賣了弗雷達的爸爸
Ma, you snitched on Freda's dad?
是的 沒錯
Yeah, I snitched.
那又如何 我告發了他
So what? I snitched.
我出賣了他
I snitched.
我這輩子也就特麼只出賣過一次
That was the only damn time I ever snitched.
結果他和我爸關在一起了
And he ends up on... in lock-up with our father.
媽 盧修斯和他被殺有關係嗎
Ma, did Lucious have something to do with his murder?
那個男人特別危險 知道嗎
That was a very dangerous man, okay?
他可以毫不眨眼地
He would've killed all of us,
殺了我們所有人
without batting an eye.
弗雷達呢
And Freda?
你知道的 有其父必有其子
You know that apple didn't fall far from the tree.
所以我才叫你遠離她 賈馬爾
So I need you to let her go, Jamal.
太危險了
It's dangerous.
這是為了大家好 好嗎
For all of us, okay?
好了
Okay.
奶奶
Grandma?
-嗨 我們可以走了嗎 -我們是要去表演現場嗎
- Hey, ready to go? - We're going to the show.
是的 奶奶但我們得趕緊
Yes, ma'am, but we have to leave right now,
趁我爸還沒回家換衣服
before my father comes home to get dressed.
好了 朗達已經為你選了一件漂亮的禮服
All right, Rhonda picked out a beautiful gown for you.
你可以在後台的休息室裏換上 好嗎
You can get dressed backstage in the greenroom, okay?
走吧
Let's go.
德懷特不希望我去嗎
Dwight doesn't want me there?
噢 不不不 他只是
Oh, n-n-n-no, he's just...
他只是太緊張了 僅此而已
He's very nervous, that's all.
今晚對他來說很重要
It's a big night for him.
這是要去哪呢
Going somewhere?
我得借用下你的電話
I'm gonna need your phone.
怎麼能讓這麼美的女士一個人走紅毯呢
A woman that beautiful shouldn't walk the red carpet alone.
要不要借我的胳膊用用
You want my arm to fall off?
別鬧了 比利·迪伊
Shut up, Billy Dee.
我聽說 某人還缺一位美國之聲的男伴
I heard somebody needed a date for the ASAs.
是啊 你知道 卡蘿爾又開始酗酒了 所以
Yeah, well, you know, Carol's back drinking again, so...
好吧 卡蘿爾算是客人
Well, Carol's more of a plus one.
算不上男伴
Not a date.
-寶貝 -嗯
- Baby? - Hmm?
我給你帶了件禮物
I got you something.
這是什麼
What is that?
你在逗我嗎
A joke?
打開看看
Open it.
是什麼把戲嗎
Is this a trick?
快打開吧
Open it.
噢 我的天
Oh, my...
噢 噢 噢 噢
Ooh-hoo-hoo! Ooh.
我幫你戴上吧
Let me put it on you.
這一定和一輛跑車
This must have been as much
一樣貴 對嗎
as a sports car, huh?
比法拉利貴了點
A little more than a Ferrari
但沒有蘭博基尼那麼貴
but less than a Lamborghini.
噢 天
Oh, my.
看看這手鏈
Look at that.
是啊 不過就我說 今晚是屬於我們的 琦琦
Yeah, the way I see it, tonight is our night, Cook.
我是說 這不就是我們一直夢想的事嗎
I mean, this is what we dreamed about way back
那時我們還開著一輛老爺車
when we were selling CDs out of the back
在費城倒賣CD呢
of that old hooptie in Philly.
我們賣的還不止CD呢
Among other things we were selling.
我知道這天一定會到來 只是我不知道
I knew we'd get here, I just didn't know
居然要這麼長的時間
it was gonna take us this long.
聽 你聽到了嗎
See, you hear that?
聽到了 我挺喜歡這段的 但是
Yeah, I kind of like the little riff, but the, um...
-歌詞太爛了 -盧修斯
- ...lyrics suck. - Lucious.
這首歌講的是一個男人愛上了
The song is about a man who's in love with a woman
一個不愛他的女人
who don't love him back.
我發誓 我無法想像和除了你之外的人一起走紅毯
I swear, I couldn't imagine going with anyone but you.
寶貝
Baby,
這專輯一定會大賣的
this album... is gonna be big.
我有預感
I can feel it.
還記得我們以前
Remember we used to have
給駕駛座邊上的門綁了好多膠布
to duct-tape the driver's side of the door
以防你掉下去嗎
so you wouldn't fall out?
-噢 我們以前真是夠潦倒啊 -是啊 那時你還提到
- Oh, we was so raggedy back then. - Yeah, and you'd talk
如果走紅毯你想穿什麼 想致什麼辭
about what you wanted to wear and what you were gonna say.
你跟我說 我最好不要在紅毯上開口
And you told me I couldn't say nothing on the red carpet
因為我只會說蠢話
'cause I would just sound stupid,
所以由你來致辭
so you was going to do the talking.
你過去可是一直在說傻話呢
You was always saying stupid stuff back then.
現在也一樣 真的沒怎麼變
Ain't nothing changed, really.
所以 這就是你讓我陪你的原因嗎
So, is that why you're taking me?
是的 還有 我真的很懷念你的翹臀
That and... I really miss that booty of yours.
嗯 我知道
Mm-hmm, I know you do.
我知道 每次我走在前面 你都盯著我的屁股
I know you're looking at it while I'm walking away.
我已經很努力想轉移視線了
I'm trying not to.
你的嘴可真甜呀
You're such a flirt.
放開我
Get off me.
你到底想怎樣
What the hell are you doing?
只是聽命於上級
Just following the boss man's orders.
沒有對你無禮的意思 安德雷
No disrespect, Andre.
你也是 奶奶
You, too, Granny.
快點 讓他們進去
Come on. Get 'em in there.
嗨 至少你們這還有電視
Hey, at least you got a TV in there.
你爸爸還是希望你能看美國之聲的
Daddy wanted you to be able to watch the ASAs.
54年了
For 54 years,
-美國之聲音樂獎 -祝你們看得開心
- the American Sound Awards - Enjoy the show.
為音樂界定義了優秀的標準
have defined excellence in music...
每年 最受世界歡迎的音樂家和藝人
Every year the world's favorite musicians and artists
齊聚一堂 紐約城最受期待的夜晚
come together to shine and be a part of
星光璀璨
New York City's most anticipated night of the year.
歡迎來到美國之聲音樂頒獎典禮
Welcome to the ASAs.
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh
♪ Ooh, ooh
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh
♪ Okay, okay, okay
♪ You're stupid funky
♪ I'm stupid fly
♪ Don't make no sense
♪ But that's all right
♪ Don't need no money
♪ Boy, I'm a dime
♪ You call me lady
♪ I'll call you guy
♪ Ooh, babe, you got a good thing coming
♪ F-A-B-U-L-O-U-S, I'm fabulous
♪ I know I'm fabulous, I know, I know I'm fabulous
哈基姆 看這
Hakeem, here!
♪ I know I'm fabulous
♪ I know, I know I'm fabulous
哈基姆
Hakeem!
♪ I know, I know I'm fabulous
♪ f-a-b-u-l-o-u-s
♪ I'm fabulous
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh
弗雷達 快看這
Freda, right here!
弗雷達 看這 你看上去美極了 弗雷達
Freda, right here, you look great! Freda!
今晚的重頭戲就是里昂一家
The big story tonight is the Lyons performing
帶來他們全新的家族之歌
their brand-new Family Anthem.
這次表演能夠不辜負之前的大肆宣傳嗎
Can it live up to the relentless hype?
今晚您將在舞台上見證
What you will see on that stage tonight
真正的一家子
is a real family.
是的 看見沒 我們不是脫線家族
Yeah, see, we're not the Brady Bunch,
我們也不是帕特裏奇一家
we're not the Partridges.
去他的 我們更不是傑克遜家族
Hell, we ain't even the Jacksons.
我們是里昂一家
We are the Lyons.
♪ I'm fabulous
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh
能拍下你的獨照嗎 哈基姆
Can we get you alone, Hakeem?
再往後退幾步 謝謝
Just a few more steps back. Thank you.
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh
♪ Go tell your mama
♪ Go tell your friends
♪ Get you some follows on Instagram
確實 盧修斯時不時
Yeah, Lucious may drive us all
會讓我們很抓狂
a little crazy every now and again,
但他是我們的國王
but he's our king.
他是天才
And he's a genius.
他也是我們能成為音樂界第一家族的原因
And he's the reason why we are the first family of music.
謝謝
Thank you.
♪ Ooh, babe, you got a good thing coming
♪ f-a-b-u-l-o-u-s
-現在和我們一起的是
- REPORTER: We're here
♪ I'm fabulous
賈馬爾·里昂 他是美國之聲
with Jamal Lyon, who is the most
提名最多獎項的藝人
nominated artist at the ASAs.
-恭喜你呀 -非常感謝
- Congratulations. - Thank you very much.
賈馬爾 今晚你邀請了哪位作伴嗎
So, Jamal, do you have a special someone with you tonight?
看這 D總監
Over here, man! D-Major!
不 我沒有
Nah, not at all.
今晚我是一個人來的 我很驕傲
I'm here all by myself and proud of it.
我聽說你最近在錄製
Well, I hear that you're working
《黑與白》這張專輯
on the Black and White album.
能不能和我們分享下進程呢
Care to share any updates on that?
好的 我現在擱置這個專輯了
Yes, I'm shelving it.
整張專輯嗎
The whole thing?
噢 看來里昂家族遇到點麻煩事了
Oh, it sounds like there's trouble in the Lyon family.
不 不 怎麼會呢 不是的
No, no. Come on, no.
只是我想製作一張屬於自己的專輯
But I need to make an album that's for me,
而不是迎合父母 所以
not for my parents, so...
祝你們今晚玩得開心
y'all enjoy tonight's performance.
今晚將是最後一次我與家人同台演出
It's the last time you'll see me onstage with my family.
以上來自我們的獨家新聞
You heard it here first.
你這是做什麼
What are you doing?
♪ Ooh, babe, you got a good thing coming
♪ f-a-b-u-l-o-u-s
♪ I'm fabulous
嗨 喲 馬爾
Hey, yo, Mal.
喲 真是太瘋狂了
Yo, this is crazy.
每個人都在喊我的名字 好像我是個超級巨星還是什麼的
Everybody's shouting my name like I'm a star or something.
-你就是巨星啊 弗雷達 -嗯
- Well, you are a star, Freda. - Mmm.
喲 等著今晚結束
Yo, after all this is done, um,
我們得好好談下你離開帝國的事
we should talk about you leaving Empire.
我會讓你換個形象 換個經紀人
I'll set you up with a new label, new management.
所有事物 今晚過後 世上所有事物
Everything. Ev-Every label in the world's
都會想和你搭上關係 你知道嗎
going to want you after this, you know?
我現在在帝國挺好的呀
Well, I'm good at Empire.
那我們的專輯怎麼辦
What about our album?
我們肯定有辦法 知道嗎
We good, all right?
相信我
Trust me.
離開帝國吧
Get away from Empire.
♪ f-a-b-u-l-o-u-s
♪ I'm fabulous
♪ I know I'm fabulous
♪ I know, I know I'm fabulous
♪ f-a-b-u-l-o-u-s
♪ I'm fabulous.
我很高興 我的經歷可以激勵其他人
I'm so glad that my life story is inspiring others.
我母親因為精神疾病而自殺
And if the pain and despair that I suffered
如果我在此之後經歷的痛苦和絕望
after losing my mother to mental illness...
如果我的經歷可以讓一個年輕人 不再感到孤立無援
if it helps one young boy feel less alone in this world,
那一切都是值得的
then it's all worth it.
不覺得他看起來有點胖嗎
Does he look fat?
上電視就是顯人胖 再說他現在又不節食了
The TV adds ten pounds, plus he broke his diet.
他怎麼會有這樣的房間
Why does he have a room like this?
為了關別人嗎
To lock people up?
這是安全屋 奶奶
It's a panic room, Grandma.
安保公司建的
Security company installed it.
我母親過世以後
Music gave me the strength to keep going
音樂給了我前行的力量 我相信
after my mother passed away, and I believe...
他答應過 他不會再把我鎖起來
He promised he wouldn't lock me up again.
他們都應該知道 他是一個騙子
They should all know he's a liar
總是食言
and a promise-breaker.
聽聽他在外面這麼撒謊
Listen to him tell his lies out there.
因此我將今夜獻給我的母親
And so I'm dedicating tonight to my mother.
謝謝
Thank you.
♪ I might not make it, I might not make it...
好 讓我來捋一捋
Okay, let me get this straight.
首先 你們兩位共同管理帝國公司
First, you two run Empire together,
而今晚你們一起出現在紅毯上
and now you two are on the red carpet tonight.
呃
Ugh.
所以 這是不是意味著琦琦和盧修斯
So, does this mean Cookie and Lucious Lyon are...?
嗨 琦琦
Hey, Cookie!
嗨 琦琦 你好
Hey, Cook! Hi Cookie!
不好意思 姑娘
Excuse me, girl.
CEO的工作永遠沒有盡頭
A CEO's job is never done.
我馬上回來
I'll be right back.
嗨 你們都知道帝國公司
Hey, y'all know Empire
是從我的車庫起步的 對吧
started in my garage, right?
不好意思給我點時間
Excuse me one sec.
-羅瑞塔 -嗨 姑娘
- Loretha! - Hey, girl!
嗨 真高興你來了
Hey, good to see you.
過來這裏 嗨
Come here. Hey.
卡蘿爾 走開
Carol, walk away.
好嗎 在我
Okay? Walk away
拽下你這個酒鬼
before I drag your drunk ass
的尿布之前 給我滾
by your nappy weave.
好嗎
Okay?
你真香
You smell good.
-謝謝 -你真好看
- Thank you. - You look pretty.
-你也是 回家吧 安全到家 -好的
- You, too. Go home. Get home safely. - Okay.
看著她離開
Make sure she leaves.
好
Yeah.
-你好 你好 -我們走 把她帶走
- Hi, hi. - Let's go, get her out.
謝謝 謝謝 謝謝
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
弗雷達 弗雷達
Freda, Freda!
噢 弗雷達
Oh, Freda!
噢 我的天 你好 弗雷達
Oh, my gosh. Hi, Freda.
-我一直就覺得
- I always thought you were
你還可愛和好有才 -謝謝 卡蘿爾小姐
so cute and talented. - Thank you, Miss Carol.
-你還好嗎 -嗯 好 好
- You all right? - Um, yeah, yeah.
需要我幫你叫專車嗎
You need me to call you a Uber?
不 不 不 不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no,
不過你知道我需要你幫什麼嗎
but you know what I need for you to do?
護送我進去行嗎
I need for you to escort me up in this place
我好甩掉盧修斯的人
so I can get Lucious' people off my tail.
-我還有很多採訪 -你有採訪
- I got more press to do. - You got press to do?
-你在說什麼
- What you talking about,
你還有很多採訪 -是的 我還有其他採訪
you got more press to do? - Yeah, I got more press.
-你以為你比我更厲害還是怎樣 -冷靜
- You think you're better than me or something, huh? - Come on.
你知道嗎 你根本不會出現在這地方
You know what? You wouldn't even be here
要不是盧修斯因為
if Lucious didn't feel guilty
對你父親做的事感到愧疚
about what he did to your daddy.
請來這邊
This way, please.
-來吧 我們走 -是吧 食人鼠
- Come on, let's go. - Yeah, hood rat.
你爸爸啊
Your daddy.
不要用你的髒手碰我
Get your hands off me.
♪ Boom, boom, boom, boom
♪ Bang, bang, bang, bang
♪ Boom, boom, boom, boom...
♪ They askin', "Why you do that, baby?"
♪ I'm wildin' on the block, like, "Why you do that, baby?"
♪ They wonder...
♪ I like the way you rhyme and how you grew that daisy.
這是你女兒嗎
That's your little girl?
是的 是我女兒
Yeah, that's my girl.
-你爸爸 -名字是弗蘭克·蓋澤斯
- Your daddy. - Name was Frank Gathers.
盧修斯·里昂
Lucious Lyon!
你和我 我們是一條繩子上的螞蚱
You and me, we cut from the same tree.
盧修斯·里昂
Lucious Lyon!
好吧 安德雷在哪裏
Okay, uh, where's Andre?
嗯 我想他跟朗達在一起
Um, I think he's in there with Rhonda.
我看到她來了 一直在找安德雷
I saw her go in. She was looking for him,
-但是找不到他 -不
- but she couldn't find him. - No.
好吧 呃 不不不
Okay, well, n-n-n-no,
不要拍家庭照片 除非我們
no family picture until we get...
求你了
Come on.
你父親不希望你這樣 讓我來幫你
Your father didn't want this for you. Let me help you.
他深愛著你
He loved you so much
即便你砍下他的右臂
that if you cut off his right arm,
他也會張開左臂 擁抱你
he'd reach over and hug you with his left one.
你根本不會出現在這地方
You wouldn't even be here if Lucious
要不是盧修斯因為對你父親做的事感到愧疚
didn't feel guilty about what he did to your daddy.
你爸爸到底對你做了什麼
What the hell your daddy do to you?
盧修斯對我來說一直像一位父親 你知道的
Lucious has been like a father to me, you know that.
你居然覺得這是件好事
And you think that's a good thing.
等他拋棄你了 就自我安慰吧
Just brace yourself for when he abandons you, too.
離帝國公司遠遠的
Get away from Empire.
離那個男人遠遠的
Stay away from that man.
不 不 不 住手 弗雷達 不
No, no, no. Stop, Freda, no!
按住槍
Get the gun!
盧修斯 你中槍了嗎
Lucious? Are you hit?
我沒事 她沒射中
I'm okay. She missed.
媽 媽
Mom! Mom!
賈馬爾
Jamal!
叫... 天哪 你為什麼要站出來
Call... boy, why you standing there?
賈馬爾
Jamal.
好的
Okay.
賈馬爾 賈馬爾 看著我
Jamal, Jamal. Look at me.
你會沒事的 好嗎
You gonna be all right, okay?
不 不 不
No, no, no!
說句話
Say something.
我們走吧
Let's go.
賈馬爾 你會挺過來的
Jamal, you're gonna make it.
噢 天哪 不 請別
Oh, God, no, please!
醒醒 孩子 說句話
Wake up, boy. Say something.
說句話
Say something...
不 不 不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no, no...
嗨 瑟斯
Hey, Thirsty!
把該死的門打開 哥們 讓我出去 我弟弟受傷了
Open the damn door, man. Let me out of here. It's my brother!
現在播報新聞
As we reported at the top of the program,
今年的美國之聲頒獎典禮取消了
this year's ASA ceremony was canceled...
瑟斯
Thirsty!
這是第一次
...for the first time ever in...
打開門 瑟斯 快點 哥們
Open the door, Thirsty! Come on, man!
超級巨星賈馬爾·里昂
Superstar Jamal Lyon
在紅毯上受到槍擊
was tragically shot on the red carpet.
根據紅毯上目擊者的證詞
According to eyewitness testimony from the carpet,
這一可怕槍擊事件的嫌疑人
the horrific shooting was committed
是帝國公司的另一位藝人
by another Empire artist,
一夜成名的說唱歌手弗雷達·蓋澤斯
upstart rapper Freda Gathers,
她的藝名是弗雷達·蓋茨
who goes by the stage name Freda Gatz.
弗雷達原本籍籍無名
Freda was plucked from obscurity
今年由帝國公司CEO一手挖掘
by Empire CEO Lucious Lyon earlier this year,
很快被稱為盧修斯發現的奇跡
and was quickly labeled his prodigy
以及帝國從落魄中
and the face of Empire's
復興起來的標誌
revived Gutter Life imprint.
噢 我的天
Oh, my God.
有消息稱 最近幾周
Sources indicate that in recent weeks,
弗雷達與受害者越來越親近
Freda had grown closer to her victim,
甚至和他共同合作歌曲
even collaborating on new tracks with him.
26歲的黑人男性
26 year-old black male,
胃部槍傷
gunshot wound to the stomach.
-沒有出口傷 可能有內出血 -準備2號手術室
- No exit wound, might be internal bleeding. - Prep OR 2.
媽媽 我沒事 媽媽 我很好
Mom, I'm okay, Mom. I'm all right.
睜開 賈馬爾 睜開眼睛 看著我
Keep... Jamal, keep your eyes open. Look at me!
一直看著我 孩子
Don't you take your eyes off me, boy.
睜開眼睛
Open your eyes.
-發生了什麼 爸爸在哪裏 -我在這 我沒事
- What happened? Where's Dad? - I'm here. I'm fine.
-他沒事 他沒事 -你照顧好我兒子
- He's fine. He's fine. - You take care of my boy.
我們需要更多數據
We need more A-positive stat.
賈馬爾 你會沒事的
Jamal, you're going to be fine.
醫生 他們會幫你包紮
Doctors... they're just gonna patch you back up.
我們沒有時間等了
We don't have time to wait.
-快動手術 -讓一讓 大家
- Get him for surgery. - Let's move, people!
-馬上 馬上 -不 不 不 賈馬爾
- Now! Now! - No, no, no, Jamal!
對不起 你不能進去
I'm sorry, this is as far as you can go.
我必須走了
I got to go...
帶他們去手術等候室
Take them to Surgical Waiting.
-琦琦 不會有 -把你的手拿開
- Cookie, it's gonna be... - Get your hands off of me.
都是你的錯 你這個
This is your fault, you son of a...
嗨 把該死的照相機關上
Hey! Put them damn cameras down!
關上
Put them down!
你們拍他的照片還不夠多嗎
Hasn't he given you enough already?
琦琦
Cookie.
別碰我
Don't you touch me.
滾開 盧修斯
Get out of the way, Lucious.
弗雷達已經被警察逮捕
Freda's since been taken into police custody.
去你家人那裏
Let's get to your family.
至今還不清楚動機
So far no motive has been revealed.
根據報道 賈馬爾·里昂正在進行
According to reports, Jamal Lyon is undergoing.
我們走
Let's go.
緊急手術 尚未脫離危險狀態
emergency surgery and remains in critical condition.
超級巨星賈馬爾·里昂在紅毯上
Superstar Jamal Lyon was tragically shot
悲劇性地受到槍擊
on the red carpet.
如果你剛剛打開我們節目
If you're just tuning into the program,
我們很悲傷地告訴你 受人喜愛的音樂人
we are saddened to report that beloved musician
賈馬爾·里昂遭遇槍擊
Jamal Lyon has been shot...
不好意思
Excuse me.
你有什麼消息嗎
Do you have any news yet?
沒有 夫人
No, ma'am.
-他們會告訴你的 -你半小時以前就這麼說了
- They'll let you know. - You said that 30 minutes ago.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
-媽 -什麼
- Ma. - What?
那是我的孩子
That's my baby.
那個賤人射中了我的寶貝
That evil bitch shot my baby.
她的目標是盧修斯
She shot at Lucious.
賈馬爾擋在了前面
And Jamal just stepped in front of the bullet.
冷靜 媽媽
Come on, Mom.
他怎麼樣了
How is he?
-他怎麼樣了 -在那邊
- How is he? - There you are.
-賈馬爾怎麼樣了 -坐下
- How's Jamal? - Sit down.
他在
He's...
他還在手術中
He's still in surgery,
而且他們什麼都不說
and they're not telling us anything.
德雷 他們什麼消息都不說
Dre, they're not telling us anything.
你去哪了
Where were you?
我到處找你
I was looking everywhere for you.
聽我說 現在不是時候 好嗎 寶貝
Look, not now, okay, babe?
我不敢相信他們還在公佈美國之聲大獎
I can't believe they're giving an ASA update.
今年美國之聲最佳說唱歌手
ASA for Rapper of the Year
獲獎者是 斯科瑞
goes to... Skrills.
最大獎項即將公佈
Finally we come to the big prize,
美國之聲今年最佳歌曲
the ASA for Best Song of the Year.
求你了 拜託 我們需要理由 來微笑一下
Please, come on. We need a reason to smile.
賈馬爾 拜託了
Jamal, come on.
今年美國之聲最佳歌曲是
The ASA for Best Song of the Year goes to...
P.O.C的《Dreaming》
"Dreaming" By P.O.C.
謝謝
Thank you.
他們分散了選票
They split the votes.
你和賈馬爾 你爭我搶
All that fighting, you and Jamal.
都是為了什麼 一無所獲
For what? Nothing?
SSK字幕組
卡蘿爾·哈德威腦子不清醒 她不會成為
Carol Hardaway's a wreck. She won't be
-可靠的目擊證人 -我們還是應該給她施加壓力
- a reliable witness. - We should still press her.
我不想對她那麼做
I don't want to do that to her,
而且 我不需要她
and besides, I don't need her.
今晚美國之聲現場發生的事情 絕不是偶然
What happened tonight at the ASAs, that wasn't random.
正好讓我聯繫上了 我一直在調查的事
It touches right on the nerve of what I've been building on.
20年前有人死在盧修斯·里昂手下
Bodies were dropping under Lucious Lyon 20 years ago.
邦基·坎貝爾透露過 盧修斯謀殺了四個毒販
Bunkie Campbell told someone he murdered four drug dealers.
你要給我搞大事嗎
Are you gonna bring me something big?
一直如此 你知道我的工作方式
Always, but you know how I like to work.
我喜歡仔細地把事情拼到一起
I like to put things together carefully.
盧修斯·里昂的前未婚妻 被他的兒子哈基姆搞大了肚子
Lucious Lyon's ex-fiancee, pregnant by his son, Hakeem.
她願意站出來說話嗎
And she's willing to talk?
還沒有 但我打算說服她
Not yet, but I'm planning to persuade her.
有誰需要咖啡
Anybody want coffee?
我來一杯
I'll take one.
我和你一起去
I'll go with you.
我猜我們現在該吃點東西了
I guess we're on snack patrol now.
嗯
Huh?
你介意我坐這兒嗎
You mind if I sit down?
該死的 琦琦
Damn, Cookie.
如果你聽到了我對賈馬爾說的話
If you heard the things I said to Jamal.
也許我媽當初把我淹死了更好
Maybe it would've been better if my mama had drowned me.
別說了
Stop.
你生來就活在人間地獄中
You were born into a living hell.
你也沒有辦法
That you can't help.
但我知道 你心裏
But I know, deep down,
你的所作所為都是為了家人好
you want to do what's right for your family.
我知道
I know it.
里昂先生和夫人
Mr. And Mrs. Lyon?
有人稱 今晚的事件更證明了
Some are saying tonight's incident is more proof
嘻哈文化滋生暴力
that hip-hop culture breeds violence.
但現在 賈馬爾·里昂會不會因此付出生命的代價
But now, could Jamal Lyon end up paying for it with his life?
考慮到隱私 我們將留在現場
...citing privacy concerns, but we'll remain on the scene...
關於弗雷達·蓋澤斯 好像有傳言
...by Freda Gathers, seems to be a message...
看 有人出來了
Look! Someone just came outside.
-她是誰 -借過
- Who is she? - Excuse me.
抱歉 抱歉 女士
Excuse me. Excuse me, ma'am.
有沒有關於賈馬爾的消息
Is there any news about Jamal?
你是這家裏的一員嗎 女士
Are you part of the family, ma'am?
您是否知道賈馬爾·里昂的狀況
Do you have any news about Jamal Lyon's condition?
是 我是這家的成員
Yes, I am part of the family.
女士 您叫什麼名字
Ma'am, what is your name?
砰
Boom.
您有新消息嗎
Do you have any new information?
砰
Boom.
您和盧修斯·里昂是什麼關係
What is your relationship to Lucious Lyon?
砰
Boom.